{
    "id": "5b2a0a5ae5584d419b6e83bb842bce45",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar And Vocabulary Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "5a63a66f8cb14639b5a679bd3d077ac7",
            "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She is ……………………. to take her own decisions now.",
                    "description": "When enough modifies an adjective, it goes after that adjective.",
                    "answers": [
                        "enough mature",
                        "mature enough",
                        "too mature"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Girls mature ………………………….. than boys.",
                    "description": "Earlier is the correct comparative expression.",
                    "answers": [
                        "more early",
                        "earlier",
                        "more earlier"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The body ………………………. maturity earlier than the mind.",
                    "description": "There is no preposition after reach.",
                    "answers": [
                        "reaches",
                        "reaches at",
                        "reaches to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………… we will see you tomorrow.",
                    "description": "Maybe means perhaps. May in may be is an auxiliary verb indicating probability.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Maybe",
                        "May be",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Many elderly people don’t have the …………………………. to travel.",
                    "description": "Means can mean money, resources or funds.",
                    "answers": [
                        "mean",
                        "means",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "How could anyone be so ……………………..?",
                    "description": "Mean can mean malicious or vicious.",
                    "answers": [
                        "mean",
                        "means",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t want anyone to ………………………. in my affairs.",
                    "description": "To meddle is to interfere.",
                    "answers": [
                        "meddle",
                        "mettle",
                        "medal"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It takes a lot of ………………………. to fight bulls.",
                    "description": "Mettle means courage.",
                    "answers": [
                        "meddle",
                        "metal",
                        "mettle"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The lawyer tried to ………………………….. between the company and the union.",
                    "description": "To mediate is to intervene or negotiate. To meditate is to think, ponder or reflect.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "mediate",
                        "meditate",
                        "modulate"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She spends hours admiring ……………………….. in the mirror.",
                    "description": "We use the reflexive pronoun when the object refers to the same person as the subject.",
                    "answers": [
                        "her",
                        "herself",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t approve of whisky but I am not averse …………………….. a glass of wine now and then.",
                    "description": "Averse is followed by to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "to",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Cats have an aversion ………………………. wet.",
                    "description": "The to here is a preposition. When to is a preposition, it is followed by a noun or ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to get",
                        "to getting",
                        "of getting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}